<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software and Ops</title>
    <link>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Software and Ops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 13:48:52 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://victor.cloudflavor.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vue vs React Part I (Vue&#39;s prolific simplicity)</title>
      <link>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/2021/01/vue-vs-react-part-i-vues-prolific-simplicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 13:48:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/2021/01/vue-vs-react-part-i-vues-prolific-simplicity/</guid>
      <description>Yep, it&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of 2021 and it&amp;rsquo;s one of those posts! I decided there aren&amp;rsquo;t enough of them on the internet and thought i might indulge in writing one 😆.
This comes from my perspective as a beginner in both frameworks and i will be talking about vue 2 not vue 3, i haven&amp;rsquo;t rolled out, ported or even read anything on vue 3 yet.
Initially i wanted to write a single post, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of example code to cover, so i decided to split it in three instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC Web</title>
      <link>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/2021/01/grpc-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 03:06:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/2021/01/grpc-web/</guid>
      <description>In this posts we will explore how to make a frontend, written in React, talk to a gRPC service.
gRPC and the web Browsers can&amp;rsquo;t talk to gRPC services natively so the solution came in the form of a proxy that could translate the frontend http requests made by the browser to gRPC calls that the backend gRPC service could understand.
These solutions are differently implemented in both libraries that emerged to tackle this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 05:02:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Victor, experienced Ops person in public/private cloud (AWS, Kubernetes) and fullstack Dev in Go/Js.
In another life i was a sysadmin @AT&amp;amp;T, a software developer @Red Hat and a DevOps @adidas.
Currently a software dev @dectris where i write and maintain kubernetes services for x-ray detectors.
Sometimes i work on open source projects @Cloudflavor.
In my free time i like to travel, hike and freedive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your life with gRPC easier</title>
      <link>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/2020/12/make-your-life-with-grpc-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 05:02:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victor.cloudflavor.io/2020/12/make-your-life-with-grpc-easier/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year i started to write a lot of gRPC services and after a while fiddling around, there are things that are worth mentioning for the uninitiated.
Design documentation I found the Google API design documentation useful for making you adopt some standards for your APIs early on. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to follow it word by word, but overall it definitely has its use. From mapping http methods to gRPC methods to naming conventions that help you design your API intuitive for future growth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
